Guide to the William Sloane Coffin, Jr. Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1916-2003; Accession 2004-M-056
  - Videotapes
    - "Toward the Well-Being of Humanity: Lessons Learned" [commercially produced], 2002 April 3; 1 (Box 88)
      Southwestern University, Shilling Lecture Series; lectures by Marian Wright Edelman, Coffin, and John Maguire, with introduction by Maguire-good audio/visual.
    - "A Fete for Bill Coffin with his Friends", 2003 October 30; 1 (Box 89)
      Luncheon in honor of Coffin with speeches by Margot Coffin, Cora Weiss, John Maguire, Andy Young, Bill Moyers, Warren Goldstein, Coffin, and a prayer by Joe Hough-relatively poor audio/visual.
    - "Memories of the 275th Anniversary Year at the Centre Congregational Church in Lynnfield" [commercially produced], Undated; 1 (Box 90)
      Video made for celebration of anniversary year events, including a speech by Coffin-low budget, but good audio/visual.
  - Born digital files (Reel 91–94)
- Additional Material, 1959-1975; 1966-1968; Accession 2005-M-059
  This accession was transferred from the basement of Battell Chapel and contains a wide variety of materials almost entirely dating between 1966 and 1968. Materials are arranged alphabetically by topic and folder headings are largely derived from the original folders. Most of the materials are clippings, pamphlets, and other collected material. There is very little correspondence and it is all found within topical folders. The small amount of writings and sermons are listed under those headings.
  Materials in this accession relate primarily to issues of importance to Coffin in the late 1960s, especially the Vietnam War. Materials on Coffin's anti-Vietnam War activism can be found in the following folders: American Clergymen's Committee for Vietnamese War Relief; Boston 5 Trial; Cambodia; Canada; Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors; civil disobedience; Clergy and Laymen Concerned about Vietnam; draft; Interfaith Council for Peace; Johnson, Lyndon B.; Lynd, Staughton; religious groups on Vietnam; and Vietnam. Another topic relatively well documented in the accession is civil rights. Materials relating to civil rights can be found under the folder headings black power, civil rights, Mississippi, National Association for the Advancement of Colored Persons, and W. E. B. DuBois Clubs.
  - Aging, 1967 October-November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Clergymen's Committee for Vietnamese War Relief, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Birth control/abortion, 1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Black power, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Boston 5 Trial
    - Clippings, 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Statement, 1968 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brewster, Kingman, 1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brown, John Pairman, 1968 January-February (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr., 1967 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Callahan, Dan, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Cambodia, 1967 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Canada [draft dodging], 1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Capital punishment, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Christmas cards, 1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Civil disobedience [includes 1 photograph], 1967-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Civil rights, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 17 - 19)
  - Clergy and Laymen Concerned about Vietnam, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 20 - 21)
  - Clippings, 1964-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 22 - 23)
  - College Student Personnel Institute, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Committee of Responsibility, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Connecticut, 1967, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Conscientious objectors [draft], 1967-1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 27 - 29)
  - Downtown Cooperative Ministry, Inc. [annual report], 1975 March 24 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Dwight Hall, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Easter, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Food/nutrition, 1970, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Higher education, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Income tax, Undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Institute for American Democracy, 1967 May (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Interfaith Council for Peace, 1968 January-February (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Johnson, Lyndon B. and his advisors, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Lindsay, John: decentralization of New York City schools, 1967 November 9 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Lynd, Staughton, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - McCarran Act, Undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - McCarthy for President, 1967-1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Marriages, Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Medical school, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Middle East: Banki, Judith, "Christian Reactions to the Middle East Crisis", Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Mississippi: free elections, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - National Conference for New Politics, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - National service, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 50 - 51)
  - Negotiation Now, 1967, undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - New Left, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - New University conference, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - "Open Letter-A Psychosynthesis: To Teach or to Not-Teach", Undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Paros, Lawrence, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Peace and Freedom Party, 1968 March (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Poverty, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Recent books, 1968, undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Religious groups on Vietnam, Undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Sermons and speeches, materials for, 1967-1968, undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Sermons
    - "Baccalaureate Sermon," Wells College, 1966 June (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Untitled [at Battell Chapel, Yale University], 1964 March 1 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Untitled [at Battell Chapel, Yale University], 1967 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Speeches, sermons, and writings by others/unidentified, 1959, 1966-1968 (Box 3, Folder 65 - 67)
  - Vietnam
    - International law, Undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Poetry, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - W. E. B. DuBois Clubs, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Writings
    - "Do You Undervalue Sex?" Glamour, 1964 August (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - "On the Roots of Prejudice", Undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Yale Divinity School: Reflection, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Additional Material, Accession 2005-M-099
  Also includes Accession 2006-M-056
  - Correspondence between Coffin and Michael Ferber, 1983-2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Communication and Social Change: The Verbal and Nonverbal Protest of Selected Clerical Activists Opposed to the Vietnam War, 1965-1970 [dissertation by Ellis Eugene Long, Florida State University. Includes a 1993 letter from Long to Coffin], 1971, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional Material, 1941-1982; Accession 2007-M-068
  - A, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Address book, photograph of Coffin, and book review, Circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Altar Guild, Battell Chapel, Yale University, 1941-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3 - 4)
  - B, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Battell Chapel administrative materials, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brewster, Kingman, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - C, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Clergy and Laymen Concerned About Vietnam, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 13)
  - Coffin, Catherine Butterfield, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - D, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Declinations of offers to write/speak, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - E, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - F, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Foundations, circa 1970s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - G, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - H, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hanoi venture, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - I, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - J, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - K, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - L, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - M, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Magruder, Jeb, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - McGovern presidential campaign, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - N, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - O, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - P, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Preaching engagements, Battell Chapel, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 33 - 34)
  - Preaching engagements, William Sloane Coffin, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 35 - 37)
  - R, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Recommendations, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - S, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Student recommendations [Yale student records; restricted until 2047 Jan 1], 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - T, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - U, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - W, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - XYZ, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Yale Religious Ministry, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Church of Christ in Yale University (includes budget materials for the church) [Yale administrative records; restricted until 2008 Jan 1], 1953-1972 (Box 2, Folder 47 - 52)
  - Church of Christ in Yale University, Church School [Yale administrative records; restricted until 2008 Jan 1], 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Restricted files removed from other boxes in accession, 1916-2003
    - Student recommendations [includes Yale students], 1969-1971 (Box 3)
      Student recommendations are restricted until January 1, 2047 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
- Additional Material, 1972-1976; Accession 2007-M-084
  - A, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - B, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - C, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Christian Science Monitor, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - D, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Declinations of offers to write/speak, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 10)
  - E, Circa 1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - F, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Finances, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - G, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - H, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Institute for World Order, Inc., 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16 - 18)
  - J, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - K, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - L, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - M, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - N, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - O, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - P, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Preaching engagements, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 26 - 27)
  - R, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Recommendations, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    These records are restricted until January 1, 2051
  - Resignation of William Sloane Coffin, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 30 - 32)
  - S, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - T, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - W, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Yale Hillel Foundation, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Restricted file removed from box 2
    Recommendations are restricted until January 1, 2051 as established by Yale Corporation regulations.
    - Recommendations, 1975-1976 (Box 3)
- Additional Material, 1931-2006; Accession 2010-M-066
  - Correspondence, 1939-2006
    - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - C (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
    - D (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - E (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - F (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - G (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - H (Box 2, Folder 4-6)
    - I (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - J (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - K (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - L (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - M (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
    - N (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 0 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - P (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - R (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
    - S (Box 4, Folder 6-7)
    - T (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - V (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - W (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - Y (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Z (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Subject files
    - Bioethics, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Children's rights, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Civil/human rights, 1989-2006 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Death, 1991-1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Death penalty, 1981-1998 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Draft resistance, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Drugs, 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Economic injustice, 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Education, 1980-1998 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Environment, 1990-1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Gun control, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Homosexuality, 1980-2005 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Inscribing the Text, 2002 September 5 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Interfaith Network", 1997-2005 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Intervention, 1993-2000 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Marriage/weddings, 1977-1987 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Merton Lecture, 1980 October 16 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Montgomery Fellow, Dartmouth, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - National Congress of SANE/FREEZE, 1987 November 20-22 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - National security, 1996-2006 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Nelson, Steve, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Non-proliferation of nuclear weapons, 1999-2005 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Nuclear disarmament, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Nuclear weapons, 1978-2005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Nuclear Weapons Convention, 1997 April (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Oppositions to Bush's war, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Pacific School of Religion, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Peace, 1993-2002 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Politics, legislation, and elections, 1995-2006 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Prayers, 1995-1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Purdum, Ralph Stanley, memorial service, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Religious rights, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Riverside Church
      - Disarmament Reader, Circa 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Sermons, 1978-1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Same-sex marriage, 1999-2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Vanderbilt, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - War and violence, 1992-2005 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Writings
    - Address at the 166th Convocation of Union Theological Seminary, 2001 September 5 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Another Point of View", Undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Appeals to religious communities of America, 2005 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Arms, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "The Authority of the Bible", Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Baccalaureates, 1995-1997 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Baccalaureate sermon: Colgate University, 1979 May 27 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Baptism sermon at Washington National Center, 1998 January 11 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Boden [sp?], Alison, installation sermon, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Bosnia / Herzegovina speech, Circa 1993 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Boston 5, Undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "Brave 'Nuke' World: The Exit Sign", Undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - "The Call of Abraham", Undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - "Can We Honor the Warriors but not the War?", Undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - "Caring About Central America, I-IV", 1983-1985 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Caring Is the Greatest Thing, Caring Matters Most", 2000 November 5 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "The Challenge of Disarmament", 1980 February 1 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Charge to Mary Luckey, 2000 September 24 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Chicago, Maryland, New York, Vermont, and Virginia, 2000-2003 (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - "A Christian Perspective on Civil Unions", 2000 November 2 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - "The Christian Right -- How Christian? How Right?", Undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Church of Christ, Dartmouth, 1994 October 30 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Church and University, 1990s (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Church - Worship, Undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - "Civic Responsibility in the New Millennium", 2000 September 3 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Classmates, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Coffin motto, Undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Cogito, ergo sum or Amo, ergo sum, Undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Columbia Charter Day Oration, 1987 April 13 (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Commencement speech, Westminster Choir College of Rider University, 2000 May 13 (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - "Concluding Remarks at the Ethics Network Conference", 1997 November 21 (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Credo [draft], 2000 (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - "The Dangers of Self Righteousness", 1998 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Death, Undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - "Despair Is Not an Option", 2004 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Dickenson College, Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1993 February 14 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Disarmament lecture, Undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - "Dreams Into Deeds," a Global Concerns Conference, 1996 December 28 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - "Ethical Elderhood", 2001 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Eternal Life, Undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Feed My Lambs, Undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "A Few Thoughts on Life and Death," Phillips Andover, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Flying in Unity", 1985 September 29 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "For the World to Survive", Undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Foreward: Outward Bound", Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Forward to Erik Kolbell's Beatitudes, Undated (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Forward for Robert MacAfee Brown book, Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Freedom Ride", 1977 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "God and the World's Disorders", 2002 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "God and War at Yale", 2005 April 28 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "God Bless America", 2001 October 14 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - The God I believe in, Undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "Go Gentle Into That Good Night", 1999 May 30 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "The Greatest of These", Undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Gulf War, 1991 September 28 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Hiroshima Then and Now", 1995 August 1 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - "Holy Worldliness", Undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - "Homophobia, the Bible, the Army, and the Church", Undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - "Homophobia: the Last 'Respectable' Prejudice", Undated (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Hospital chapel dedication, Undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - "How Do We Know God?", Undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - "How Should the Family View Other Faiths?", Undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - "How to Live the Easter Faith in a Good Friday World?", 1997 April 3 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - "I Have Called You by Name, You Are Mine", 1996 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Interviews, 1986-2005 (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Iowa peace speech, 1999 April 9 (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Lawyers, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Lectures, Undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Lessons and carols, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - "Lessons of the Gulf War", 1991 September 28 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - "Letters to a Young Doubter", 2005 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - "A Letter to the Churches of Vermont", Undated (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - "Let Us Be Impatient with Prejudice", Undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - "Liberty to the Captives and Good Tidings to the Afflicted", 1995 January 21 (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - "Love Has a Corporate Character", Undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - "Love, Power, and Justice", 1994 December 1 (Box 12, Folder 37-38)
    - "Make Love Your Aim", Undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - "Male and Female Created He Them", Undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - "Memorial Prayer for Richard A. Harrison", 1998 January 8 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - "Montpelier Rally", 2003 October 25 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - "Musing at Year's End", Undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - "Musing on Mortality", Undated (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - "My Son Beat Me to the Grave", Undated (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - News articles / commentaries, 2000-2004 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - The Non-Proliferation Treaty, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Notes, Undated (Box 13, Folder 3-7)
    - "Nuclear Weapons: The Case for Their Abolition", 2002 October 19 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Nukes Forever? The Case for Their Abolition", Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - "On Self-Righteousness and Immoral War", 2005 March 20 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - "Open Letter to the Kansas Board of Education", 1999 August 13 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Outagamie Bar Association, Undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Pastor as spiritual leader, 1991 January (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - People for American Way, Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - "The Peril and Promise of Religion", 2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - "Peter, Paul, and Mary", Undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "A Politically Engaged Spirituality", 2005 August 28 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - "The Politics of Compassion", 1997 October 15, undated (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
    - "Prayer for Dr. Howard Koh", 1997 October 15 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "Prepare the Way of the Lord," Riverside, 1994 December 4 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Press releases, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Protestants for the Common Good, 1996 January 27 (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Remarks for certain people, Undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Report on trip to the Soviet Union, Undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Resignation statement to the Riverside Church congregation, 1987 July 19 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Rich man and Lazarus, Undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Ripon College installation address, 1996 September 29 (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Riverside Church sermon, 1981-1990 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - "The Role of the Church: To Pursue Both Charity and Justice", Undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Sacraments, Undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - "Said the Fox to the Little Prince", Undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - "Salt of the Earth, Light of the World," sermon at the ordination of Andrea Ayvazian, 1998 December 6 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - SANE/FREEZE, 1990s (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - "Searching for Forgiveness and Justice", 2001 (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - "Self-Righteousness: The Bane of All Human Relations", 2003 (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - "A Serious Call to a Devout and Holy Life", Undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Sermon at Battell Chapel, 1972 October 15 (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Sermon at PSR graduation, Undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Sermon on the Installation of Dean Scotty McLennan, 2001 March 12 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Sermons, 1979-2001 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - "Should Nuclear Weapons Be Abolished?", Undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - "Sin and Forgiveness", Undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - "The Spiritual and the Secular: Can They Meet?," inauguration of Paul B. Ranslow, Ripon College, 1996 September 29 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - "Spiritual Crisis in the Northeast" conference, 1978 April 29 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - "Spirituality for the Long Haul -- Food for the Journey", 1989 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - "Struggling with Scripture", Undated (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - "Thanksgiving", 1996 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Third Annual Thomas Merton Lecture. "National Security and the Arms Race", 1980 October 16 (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - "Thoughts About Retribution", Undated (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Twenty-third Psalm, Norwich, 1993 July (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - "Une Passion pour le Possible", Undated (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Union Theological Seminary: opening convocation, 2001 September 5 (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - United Church of Christ (UCC) Wisconsin clergy, Undated (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - United Presbyterian Church, 189th General Assembly, 1977 June 28 (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - United Stated foreign policy, Undated (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - "United States Interventions: Past, Present -- and Future", Undated (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - "The United States, Iraq, and Nuclear Weapons", 2002 (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Untitled autobiography, Circa 1975 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
    - Untitled collection of sermons, Undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - "Upon Further Reflection", 1995 May 26 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - "Values Caught More Than Taught", Undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - "The Warhorse", 1998 May 24 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - "War Is a Coward's Escape From the Problems of Peace", 2003 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - "The War So Far", Undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - "The War: What Next?", Undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - "What Is Spirituality?", Undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - "Where Does the Heart Go to College?", Undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - "Who Is Their [sic] Big Enough to Love the Whole Planet?", 1993 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - "Who Tells You Who You Are?", 2001 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - "Why Democracy Failed in France", Undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - "Why I'm Still in the Church", Undated (Box 15, Folder 16)